LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/evan-sparago

SPARAGO, EVAN

OVERVIEW

Senior Program/Project/Client Manager with 28 years of experience in the Information Technology industry. Experienced in all aspects of project delivery, from sales to delivery to service operation.

Currently employed at OpenText Corporation as a Program & Client Manager, coordinating the delivery, and sustain of projects within the Automotive Line of Business.

Extensive experience at managing all aspects of program development with a current focus on Agile framework. Excelled at building IT Organizations and processes, communicating, and overseeing solution deliveries. Recognized for managing projects that are of high quality, on time, under budget and committed to best practices as defined by the Project Management Institute (PMI).

Received PMP certification in 2004. Twice awarded the "HP GM Account Champion of Customer Service" Award (2010, 2011). Received the "GM Global Business Services Excellence" Award in 2010. Sun Certified Programmer for Java 2 Platform 2000. Received a United States Patent, Patent No. US 7,350,185 B2 – "Web Based Macro Patterns" with Patent Date of March 25, 2008.

SKILLS

- Tools: AWS Management Console, Apigee, Atlassian JIRA, Dynatrace Synthetic and Application Performance Management, MS Office (Project, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Visio), MySQL, NetSuite, Postman, Salesforce, SharePoint, HubSpot, GitHub
- Methodologies/Frameworks/Processes: Agile, ITIL, Waterfall, GMs SDP21, Rational Unified Process (RUP)
- Documents and Diagrams: Business Requirements Definition, System Requirements Definition, Agile User Stories, Architectural Diagram, Technical Design Document, Process Flow, Project Plans, Project Timelines, Project Roadmaps, Status Reports, Financial Analysis Reports
- Competencies: Project Management and Delivery Methodologies, Global Resource
 Management, Contract Management, Change Management, Incident Management, Problem
 Management, Event Management, Process Design, Relationship Building, Organization
 Building, Outsourcing, Quality Testing & Assurance, Collaborative Decision Making,
 Communication
- Languages and Technologies: JEE, JSE, Web Services, Restful Services, Web Applications, SQL, XML, JSON, SAML, C

WORK HISTORY

COVISINT (NOW PART OF OPENTEXT) DETROIT, SOUTHFIELD

8/1/2017 TO PRESENT

Customer Success Manager (concurrent with Program Manager)

09/2012 - 09/2015

 Acted as the customer advocate, helping to build a successful relationship between the Hyundai Connected Vehicle customer and Covisint's delivery organizations.

- Participated in Marketing, Sales, Professional Services, Training and Support.
- Acted as the Project Owner in backlog grooming and daily standups.
- Provided the customer with a single point of contact for escalations, service requests and change requests. Worked with the team to create estimates and build the Statement of Work. Worked with customer to finalize Purchase Order and worked with billing to invoice.
- Acted as the Communication Liaison during Service Outage Events between the internal outage line and the customer outage line. Responsible for delivering the Root Cause Analysis and ensuring follow up actions were completed.

Program Manager (concurrent with Customer Success Manager) 09/2012 – 09/2015

- Led the Hyundai program, with an annual budget of approximately 2.5 million dollars and a 13-person global team.
- Successfully delivered monthly releases (to production).
- Worked with the Director level staff to build and staff the Delivery and Service operation organizations.
- Created and implemented ITIL Service Transition procedures for Change and Release Management.
- Created and implemented ITIL Service Operation procedures for Event Management, Incident Management, Problem Management, and Request Fulfillment.
- Identified and implemented productivity tools with processes, including Atlassian JIRA as
 a primary tool for managing backlogs (Kanban for Service Operations and scrum for
 delivery projects).
- Responsible for all executive level status and the quarterly financial report.
- Participated in product Roadmap Planning and Management.
- Created and distributed monthly operations reports providing insight into Service Level Agreement (SLA) metrics, as well as ITIL metrics and system usage and performance data.

DELIVERY MANAGER 09/2012 – 08/2015

- Led the Carlson Wagonlit Travel program, with an annual budget of approximately 2.0 million dollars and a 10-person global team.
- Successfully delivered 15 releases (to production) in 20 months.
- Srum master for backlog grooming, daily standups, and scrum ceremonies (sprint planning, sprint retrospective, sprint review).
- Traveled to customer sites to participate in roadmap planning and business reviews.
- Owned communication (internally and externally), Project Plans, Project Schedules, Scope, Issues, Risks, Finances, Metrics Reporting, and Transition to Sustain.

Page | 2 Sparago, Evan

PROGRAM MANAGER ON GM GLOBAL BUSINESS SERVICES ACCOUNT 10/2011 - 08/2012

- Program Manager for the HP Security Compliance Program Management Office (PMO)
 which was tasked with overseeing all compliance activities within GM's Global Business
 Services (GBS) Organization.
- Supervised a global staff with resources located in the US, Canada, Argentina, India and China.
- Managed and coordinated the compliance activities of all HP-owned applications.
- Supervised 25 project managers.
- Responsible for 60 application teams, 180 applications, and over 90 resources.
- Ensured that all applications completed their HP WebInspect security scans by their scheduled date, and all servers completed their Technical Security Scans (TSS).
- Ensured that all applications resolved their Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) top 10 non-compliances and IIS, Oracle, HP/UX, Win2003, Tomcat and Red Hat Linux server non-conformances

PROJECT MANAGER ON GM GLOBAL BUSINESS SERVICES ACCOUNT 10/2007 - 09/2011

- Led the sales teams of 40 customer IT requests with total revenue of just under \$13 million.
- Managed all phases of 12 projects with a combined budget of just under \$11 million.
- Received the HP GM Account Champion of Customer Service Award in 2010 for effort related to migrating 110 legacy web sites and 10,000 pages of content to SharePoint
- Received the HP GM Account Champion of Customer Service Award in 2011 for implementing the BWise toolset and rolling out to 70,000 GM Employees in support of GM's annual Ethics Certification Program
- Scrum Lead for HP's part of the Allison Transmission Divestiture which included infrastructure, database, and application migration. Met tight timelines to adhere to federal regulations governing the divestiture
- Worked as the Requirements Lead during the Plan and Define Phases of projects using GM's SDP 21 processes
- Worked as the Project Manager during the Construct to Close Phases of projects using HP's System Delivery processes.

ELECTRONIC DATA SYSTEMS (EDS) DETROIT. BRAZIL. BELGIUM

07-1998 - 09/2007

PROJECT MANAGER ON GM IDENTITY MANAGEMENT ACCOUNT

03/2005 - 09/2007

- GM Project Manager within the GMs Identity and Access Management Program Office.
- Managed the Identity Management enterprise initiative a collection of integrated systems that automatically assigns each GM Person of Interest a GM Identification Number (GMIN). Rolled out GMIN to over 250,000 people.

Page | 3 Sparago, Evan

- Supervised the scope, construction, testing and deployment of the systems into GM's
 environment
- · Coordinated the integration of services with GM Portal, Supplier Portal and Dealer Portal.
- Managed the Single Sign-On enterprise initiative a single sign-on system for GM employees.

ARCHITECT AND SYSTEMS INTEGRATOR

01/1998 - 02/2005

- · Worked extensively in Belgium and Brazil.
- Systems Integrator for GM's Brazilian Online Web Vehicle Sales Portal called Hermes NG a web based vehicle sales portal which encompassed 13 companies and 27 program partners.
- Developed the application in Java using J2EE.
- Supervised the integration of the online ordering system. Participated in the architecture definition for all three Tiers, with emphasis on systems integration to global tools.
- Integrated with Global Tools (Dealer/Vehicle Locator, Oracle Vehicle Configurator) thru EJB
 calls. Integrated with GMAC Tools (Payment Estimate, Express Application) via URL
 connection calls.
- Architect for GM Europe's enterprise Web Vehicle Configurator and enterprise Web Vehicle Inquiry applications.
- Integrated a web front end (created in Java using Servlet, JSP and HTML) into GM Europe's existing Vehicle Configurator system (written in C). Deployed the system into GM Europe's Web Portal.
- Patent awarded in 2008 (US 7,350,185 B2).

DEVELOPER AND TECHNICAL LEAD

07/1998 - 12/1997

- Technical lead and developer on the various Powertrain Engineering software simulation systems.
- Worked with General Motors Research Engineers to transition mathematical models into software computational programs.
- Delivered and trained GM Divisional users in the simulation software.

EDUCATION, CERTIFICATIONS, AWARDS

- Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering State University of New York at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY
- Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering State University of New York at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY
- Electronic Data Systems Engineering Systems Developer (ESD) Program 1988/1990
- PMP certified Project Manager in 2004
- Sun Certified Programmer for Java 2 Platform 2000
- · ITIL Certified
- United States Patent, Patent No. US 7,350,185 B2 "Web Based Macro Patterns" with Patent Date of March 25, 2008
- HP GM Account Champion of Customer Service 2011 Award
- HP GM Account Champion of Customer Service 2010 Award
- GM Global Business Services 2010 Excellence Award

Page | 4 Sparago, Evan

REFERENCES CHRISTIAN ANDREWS

Strategic Account Executive at Open Text

714.814.1798

LYUDMILA MISHRA

Director at Covisint

248.787.0039

JOE GRIFFIN

ICT Manager - Chrysler/FIAT

586.344.7846

MATT POHLMAN

Enterprise Architect at Key Bank

440.453.4421

Page | 5 Sparago, Evan